In this video, we're going to take a look at Java Arrays. Let's say we have two
在本视频中，我们将看一看Java阵列。假设我们有两个人
classes, a and b, and that b is a sub class of a. And let's think about what
类a和b，而b是a的子类。让我们想一想
happens when we execute the following piece of code. So, the first thing we're
当我们执行下面的代码段时发生。所以，我们要做的第一件事
going to do is we're going to allocate an array of b's. So, this is an array that's
我们要做的是分配一个由b组成的数组。所以，这是一个数组，
supposed to hold B's, okay? And, we're going to have an array variable b here
应该是拿B的，好吗？我们在这里会有一个数组变量b
that points to it. And then, we're going to have another variable, array variable
这说明了这一点。然后，我们将有另一个变量，数组变量
A, that also points to the same array as B. But notice the type of a. So a is an
A，这也指向与B相同的数组。但是请注意a的类型。
array of A's, little a here is an array of A's, and b is typed as an array of B's.
A的数组，这里的小a是A的数组，b的类型是B的数组。
And now what we're going to do is we're going to assign into a sub zero, okay,
现在我们要做的是赋值到零下，好的，
into the first position of a, a new a object. And that should be fine, right?
放到一个，一个新的一个物体的第一个位置。那应该没问题，对吧？
Because a is an array of A's and that seems like that should work out alright.
因为a是由A组成的数组，这看起来应该可以解决问题。
Alright, so here there will be an a sitting in the first position. And then,
好的，那么这里会有一个a坐在第一个位置。然后,
we're going to access b sub zero which, because A and B point to the same array,
我们将访问b负零，因为A和B指向相同的数组，
is the same element as a sub zero. And we're going to call some method that is
是与零以下的元素相同的元素。我们将调用一些方法，即
not declared in A. Now remember, B is a sub-type of A, alright? So B has all the
不是在A中声明的，现在记住，B是A的一个子类型，好吗？所以B拥有所有的
methods of A. A but B might have more methods. And since this is an array of
A的方法A，但B的方法可能更多。由于这是一组
B's, we should be able to call all the B methods on it and yet here, when we call
，我们应该能够调用它上的所有B方法，但是在这里，当我们调用
some methods that's declared in B but not in A, we are going to get a run-time error
一些在B中声明但在A中没有声明的方法，我们将得到运行时错误
because the object stored in the array is actually an A object at the first
因为存储在数组中的对象实际上是第一个A对象
position. To understand what's going on in this example, we have to take a look at
位置。要理解本例中发生的事情，我们必须看一看
the sub typing rules in Java. So, if we use a subtype of A if B inherits from A,
Java中的子类型规则。所以，如果我们使用A的子类型，如果B继承自A，
that's one case. So if B and B inherits from A, then B is a subtype of A. And
这只是一个案例。因此，如果B和B继承自A，那么B就是A的子类型。
that's just like in Cool and, and most other object oriented languages. And
这就像Cool和和大多数其他面向对象语言一样。和
we're, we're very familiar with that from our lectures in type checking. Further
我们在我们的打字检查课上对此非常熟悉。进一步
more, type, sub typing is transitive. So if C is a subtype of B, and B is a subtype
此外，类型和子类型是可传递的。因此，如果C是B的子类型，而B是子类型
of A then C is also a subtype of A. Okay, a nd that's also completely standard. But
那么C也是A的一个子类型，这也是完全标准的。但
then there's this other rule that's not quite standard or is definitely
然后还有另一条规则，它不是很标准，或者肯定是
nonstandard. And that's that, an array of B's is a sub-type of an array of A's if
不规范。也就是说，B数组是A数组的子类型，如果
the element types are in a sub-type relationship. So if B is a sub-type of A,
元素类型处于子类型关系中。所以如果B是A的一个子类型，
then array of B is a sub-type of array of A. And Cool doesn't have anything like
则B的数组是A的数组的子类型，而Cool没有类似于
that, Cool doesn't have arrays so it wouldn't even have the opportunity to have
Cool没有数组，所以它甚至没有机会
something like that. But this is also not the way it's done in other languages that
差不多吧。但这也不是在其他语言中这样做的方式，这些语言
have objects and sub-typing. So let's take a look at our little example again and let
具有对象和子类型。让我们再看一遍我们的小例子，让我们
me explain it in a slightly different way. So, the issue here is that we have a, area
我用一种稍有不同的方式来解释。所以，这里的问题是，我们有一个面积
of memory, and it actually doesn't matter here. It's not essential that this be an
记忆，这在这里其实并不重要。这不是必须的
array. What's important is that's an updatable part of memory so that we have
数组。重要的是，这是内存的一个可更新部分，因此我们有
pointers to it. We have two pointers to it, a and b and we can, they can both read
指向它的指针。我们有两个指向它的指针，a和b，我们可以，他们都可以阅读
and write this part of memory. So this could be just a single cell, it doesn't
并写入这部分内存。所以这可能只是一个细胞，它不
have to be an array of multiple cells. But what's important is that there is some
必须是多个单元格的数组。但重要的是有一些
memory location that both of these point to, that they can both read and write,
它们都可以读取和写入内存位置，
okay? And the trouble comes and by the way, that there's a name that, that's
好吧?麻烦来了，顺便说一句，有一个名字，那就是
called Aliasing, okay? So when you have two names, two program names for the same
叫别名，好吗？因此当您有两个名称时，两个程序名称相同
part of memory that is called aliasing, and here you know, we have the, the two
内存的一部分被称为混叠，在这里，你知道，我们有，这两个
arrays, A and B, that point to the same area of memory, okay? Now, aliasing is
数组，A和B，指向相同的内存区域，好吗？现在，别名是
very common in real programs since not bad by itself but the problem in this example
在实际程序中非常常见，因为它本身并不坏，但本例中的问题
is that A and B have different types, okay? And in general, if you have aliasing
A和B有不同的类型，好吗？一般来说，如果你有别名
updatable references, okay? Meaning if two names for the same location, that location
可更新的推荐信，好吗？意思是如果同一位置的两个名字，该位置
is both readable and writable, so it can be updated through the two names. And
既可读又可写，因此可以通过这两个名称进行更新。和
those two names have different types then that is going to be unsound, okay? We're
这两个名字有不同的类型，这是不合理的，好吗？我们是
not going to have a sound type system and to see the problem, let's say here in this
不会有声音类型的系统，要看到问题，让我们在这里
case what was it? We had that B, type B was sub type of A, okay? And what did that
案子是什么？我们有B型，B型是A型的亚型，好吗？那是怎么回事呢？
mean? Well that meant is we could do a wright through this pointer, okay? And
卑鄙？好的，这意味着我们可以通过这个指针做一个写字，好吗？和
write an A object into this location and then we could read that out through this
将A对象写入此位置，然后我们可以通过以下内容读出该对象
point over here as a B object. But now, it doesn't have all the methods and, and
在这里指向一个B对象。但是现在，它没有所有的方法和，而且
fields of A and treating it as the object, we could potentially use an operation on
字段，并将其视为对象，我们可能会在
it that's undefined. And you can see that it doesn't help if we swap the roles of,
那是不确定的。你可以看到，如果我们交换一下角色，
of A and B, alright? So in particular, if we reverse the, if we reverse the
A和B，好吗？所以特别是，如果我们反转，如果我们反转
sub-typing relationship so that A was a sub type of B, we can do exactly the same
子类型关系，所以A是B的子类型，我们可以做完全相同的事情
problem because aliasing is symmetric. We just do the write through the B pointer
问题，因为别名是对称的。我们只需通过B指针执行写入
and the read out of the A pointer swapping the roles of the recent right here and we
读出A指针，在这里和我们交换最近的角色
have exactly the same problem. So in general, multiple aliases do updatable
都有完全相同的问题。因此，通常情况下，多个别名是可更新的
locations with different types is unsound, okay? And this problem actually has come
不同类型的地点是不合理的，好吗？这个问题实际上已经出现了
up in many different programming languages. Java is not the only
支持多种不同的编程语言。Java并不是唯一的
programming language to have had this issue. It's a fairly subtle aspect of type
编程语言有过这个问题。这是字体的一个相当微妙的方面
systems and in many languages have done things similar to Java where they've
系统和许多语言都做过类似于Java的事情
created a problem really for the static type system by wanting to have a
真的给静电类型的系统带来了问题，因为想要有一个
sub-typing work through arrays. Now, the standard solution or the solution that's
子类型通过数组工作。现在，标准解决方案或解决方案是
used in, I should say, in many languages and is probably most widely accepted in
我应该说，用在许多语言中，而且可能是最被广泛接受的
the programming languages research community is that you need a different
编程语言研究社区认为您需要一个不同的
sub-typing rule for arrays. So we would say, you know, the rule that is commonly
数组的子类型规则。所以我们会说，你知道，通常
used the standard solution to this problem at the type level is that to do the
在类型级别对此问题使用的标准解决方案是
following things. So you only allows sub-typing on arrays. So, you know, an
接下来的事情。因此，您只允许对数组进行子类型。所以，你知道，一个
array of B's is a sub-type in array of A's only if B and A are the same type. If B =
仅当B和A的类型相同时，B的数组才是A的数组中的子类型。如果B=
A. And if you think about that for a second, if we have an array and now we
答：如果你想一秒钟，如果我们有一个数组，现在我们
have our two pointers to it, A and B and we know the type of A the subtype or the
有两个指向它的指针，A和B，我们知道A的类型、子类型或
type of B. Well, that only h appens if the element types are, are equal. And so we
B的类型，如果元素类型是，只有h是相等的。所以我们
can't create two references to an updateable location with different types.
无法创建对不同类型的可更新位置的两个引用。
Okay, and that will guarantee soundness of, of the type, of the type system. So
好的，这将保证类型系统的可靠性。所以
Java fixes the problem differently. So instead of statically checking that array
Java以不同的方式解决问题。因此，不是静态检查该数组
accesses will all be type correct, Java does this at run time. And so whenever an
访问都将是类型正确的，Java在运行时做到这一点。所以无论什么时候
assignment is done into an array at runtime, Java checks whether the type of
在运行时对数组进行赋值，Java会检查
the object being assigned in compatible with the type of the array. So when you
分配的对象与数组的类型兼容。所以当你
say new B sub ten in Java, Java will remember inside the array that this was
假设Java中有新的Bsubten，Java会在数组中记住这是
supposed to be an array of Bs. And then whatever you assign into the array, it
应该是一组B。然后，无论您分配给数组的是什么，它都会
will check that the thing you're assigning is either a B or a sub type of B. Now,
将检查您指定的对象是否为B或子类型B。
this obviously adds an overhead on array computations so every assignment to an
这显然增加了数组计算的开销，因此对
array is going to have, have a type check on it at run time. And fortunately though,
数组将在运行时进行类型检查。不过幸运的是，
the most kinds of arrays are arrays of primitive types, in particular arrays of
大多数类型的数组都是基元类型的数组，特别是
ints and arrays of floating point numbers and these are not affected because the
整数和浮点数的数组，这些不受影响，因为
primitive types are not classes. There's no subtyping on them and so you can never
基元类型不是类。它们上没有子类型，所以你永远不能
create an array, say, of floating point numbers, with any kind of subtyping
创建一个数组，比方说，可以使用任何类型的子类型创建浮点数的数组
relationship that would result in this problem. So, so, that we're saved, or in
会导致这个问题的关系。所以，所以，我们得救了，或者在
better shape, for the primitive types, and they don't need these extra checks. But if
原始类型的形状更好，而且它们不需要这些额外的检查。但是如果
you have arrays of objects, then we do assignments into those arrays in Java,
你有对象的数组，然后我们在Java中对这些数组进行赋值，
there's additional run time overhead.
还有额外的运行时间开销。